Hey, how's it going? I'm Eddie.
What's going on, man? Nice to meet you.
All right, so first before I start, I need to know what you mean by good.
I can talk about the economy. I can talk about culture.
I can talk about all those things.
I need to know what you mean. All of them.
All of them. I'm saying immigrants are good for the economy.
They're good for culture. You think lower wages are good for the economy?
They're good for society. Where's the lower wages?
What do you mean, where's the lower wages? Where's the lower wages?
Yes, so you can look at- What's the basis for saying there are lower wages?
Sure, so you can look at like the STEM industry.
It's been in like a complete and total recession.
There's been tons of studies like from the Economic Policy Institute
that shows that companies like Tesla, companies from like Silicon Valley,
they engaged in mass firing of workers, around 35,000,
but then they hired around 12,000 H-1B visas.
And it's kind of just like just standard economic thinking.
It's not standard economic thinking.
The vast majority of economists and economic studies suggest
that there is a negligible, if no impact on wages over time from immigrants.
In fact, your colleague mentioned earlier construction.
There is actually evidence in construction, yes.
But in some industries, in some areas, there is an impact.
But overall, no. In fact, a study from the National Bureau of Economic Research
found that migrants since 1965 have raised wages-
Who's that by?
National Bureau of Economic Research.
No, hold on. That's where you publish studies.
I'm asking for the author.
Yes, I didn't memorize the names of the authors.
I know you didn't, right?
Can you give me the authors you've got?
Yeah, hold on. The study you're talking about is from Giovanni Perry,
and what he did is he didn't account for aggregation issues, nor did he-
The vast majority of studies-
Hold on, let me speak.
Please.
Yeah, thank you, right?
So listen, he didn't account for aggregation issues, right?
And when you look at like the spatial approaches that all these economists use,
you're not accounting for the fact that when immigrants come into an area,
natives leave.
If you look at an occupational approach where you look at the specific firms
that immigration's going into, like Kim, ETAL, 2013 did,
you find a net negative impact when there's a 10% increase of immigration.
You find around a 0.5% decline in wages when it comes to the specific occupations
they're going to.
All your studies are flawed.
So 0.5%, weigh that up against what I just mentioned
from the Congressional Budget Office, which is a massive boost in GDP per head,
which you're not counting for.
Massive increase in tax revenue.
Immigrants are actually funding the deficits and debts by paying way more in taxes
proportionately to the undocumented immigrants.
And what's interesting about wages is, I'm in a room full of,
I don't know what to call you anymore.
Conservatives, Republicans, fascists, I don't know.
One of you has probably said that.
One of us probably, oh yeah, correct.
I'm in a room full of correct people, but do any of you actually care about wages?
Yeah, I actually do, right?
For example, do you support raising the minimum wage?
Absolutely, and you can't do that when you're bringing all these people coming into your country.
That's not the reason the Republican Party blocks the minimum wage.
You think Republican politicians don't vote for an increase in minimum wage
because they're worried about immigration.
Did I say I voted Republican?
Well, I'm in a show that was called 25 Far-Right Republicans.
That doesn't mean I'm going to support every single Republican candidate.
Good, so you and I, let's agree.
We both support raising the minimum wage, yes?
$7.25 since 2009. It's lost 30% of its value.
If you care about wages, we should be raising the minimum wage in this country,
not scapegoating migrants who aren't the cause of our wage in this country.
You know who's causing low wages?
Billionaires, millionaires, people who won't pay fair wages to their wages
regardless of whether you are an immigrant or a native-born American.
I get the monologue, right? Now let me respond.
You had one. You had one with your one study that had a 0.5% impact.
Yeah, and your study sucked that you didn't even know who wrote it, right?
So let's get back to the point, right?
Because I don't need to know one study.
And there it goes again.
The majority of studies say that wages are not impacted by migration over time.
The majority of your studies are flawed. That's what I'm telling you.
Not my studies. Neither of us are economists. It's the economists' studies.
Don't assume who I am.
Are you an economist?
I could be.
But are you?
I'm not going to tell you.
Are you?
I'm going to major in economics, right?
Are you an economist?
No, not right now.
Okay, so when I said neither is an economist, I was correct.
Just don't assume things.
To use your favorite word.
Dude, this is nothing of substance.
Look at the red flags. They're coming up.
Let me get to the point.
That's great, but you're not an economist.
So when you talk about the CBO, one thing you're not accounting for here
is that they're assuming an equilibrium, right?
Do you know what that means?
You shouldn't make these type of assumptions.
You said earlier that unemployment is like a—
Do I know what it means? I thought we were not doing assumptions.
Okay, hold on. You mentioned we were at like 4.2% unemployment.
Yeah, that's counting people who have part-time jobs.
That's counting poverty wages.
That's how it's always been counted.
I'm against poverty wages.
Can we agree again?
Yes.
If you go to like the Ligwood Institute,
they calculated a way where it's like functional unemployment.
Okay?
If you account for things like just people who make around $25,000 a year,
people who have fallen out of the labor market,
people who only work part-time,
if you count all of those people together
and then add on the unemployment,
that's around 25% of the population.
So when you go, we don't have jobs.
We don't have people to do this, this, and that, and the other.
No, yes, we do.
Okay?
We don't have a labor shortage.
We have a good job shortage.
And when you keep bringing these people in,
they're taking those jobs.
The good job shortage is the fault of big firms, employees.
I'm an employer. I can say that.
Who hires the immigrants?
Yeah.
Employers?
Exactly.
So when you bring up these big firms,
that's the way that you fight this out.
Let me ask you a question.
You understand that, right?
So let me ask you a question.
If you got rid of all immigrants coming in tomorrow, moratorium,
you think that Republicans and employers of big firms
would suddenly raise all the wages?
You notice how you didn't answer what I said?
That's what you believe.
That's what you believe?
You pivoted the hell away from the conversation.
I'm on your subject.
Are your ankles okay?
Do you believe that wages,
I'm just wondering how naive you are,
you believe that the 1% will raise wages and the federal wage
if we stop immigration?
They will be forced to.
When you increase labor's relationship to capital, okay,
and you give labor more bargaining power
because you're tightening the supply of labor?
This is a very simplistic understanding of economics.
Okay, explain I'm wrong.
I'm telling you how you're wrong.
Because you're ignoring the fact
that when immigrants come into an area, they spend money.
They create jobs through their presence.
About one-fifth of their monthly income leaves the country.
That's a good thing also,
because you don't like USA foreign aid.
So this is the point.
They create jobs.
Don't assume that.
I came into this country.
So far, every one of my assumptions about you
has been correct.
But listen to me.
I am an immigrant.
I'm speaking from personal experience.
Get the hell out.
I don't even like,
I should get the hell out.
Yes.
Why?
I don't want you here.
Because you come here and say all this bullshit
about how Americans are lazy.
Why?
You push your left-wing politics.
I never said Americans are lazy.
I don't know why you say this.
No, they can do jobs that we don't want to do.
That's exactly what you said.
I never said those words.
When?
When did I say it?
Oh, really?
We're on YouTube.
Guys watching on YouTube,
rewind to the time where I said
immigrants are doing jobs we don't want to do.
When did I say those words?
Words that came out of my mouth.
Okay, so why do we have to bring in immigrants?
Why do we have to bring in immigrants to the country
if we have people who are going to do the jobs?
Pause.
You've been voted out.
Nice talking to you.
You're going to have to go.
You're going to have to go, bro,
to an American citizen.
Good.
Good to know where you stand on immigration.
It's not about immigration, is it?